Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we've got another episode in our series about giving a presentation.
我是Catherine，今天我们带来了一集关于做演示的系列节目。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to talk about some key elements of the topic that we're talking about.
今天我们要讨论这个话题的一些关键要素。
We're talking about a laptop computer.
我们讨论的是一台笔记本电脑。
So we're going to give some more details and characteristics about the computer and what
所以我们会提供更多关于这台电脑的细节和特性，以及它为什么
makes it so special.
如此特别。
So let's take a listen to what Mr. Ford has to say about what makes this company's computers
那么让我们听听福特先生怎么说，关于这家公司的电脑为什么
very special.
非常特别。
Now a key question you might ask yourself is what differentiates the new X420 line with
现在你可能会问自己的一个关键问题是，新的X420系列与
our previous models and also of course with some of our competitors.
我们之前的型号以及当然还有一些竞争对手相比，有什么不同。
In other words, what makes the X420 stand out from all the others?
换句话说，是什么让X420从所有其他产品中脱颖而出？
This is a key question and it's something I'd like to explore in a little depth.
这是一个关键问题，也是我想深入探讨的事情。
Firstly the X420 has a range of USPs that really make it a cut above the rest.
首先，X420有一系列独特卖点，让它真正比同类产品更胜一筹。
The first thing to mention is that the X420 is the first in a new generation of ultra-light
首先要提到的是，X420是新一代超轻
laptop computers.
笔记本电脑中的第一款。
It is only two pounds which compares very favorably with all our key competitors.
它只有两磅重，这比我们所有主要竞争对手都更有优势。
In terms of computer performance, for such a light machine it's very powerful.
在电脑性能方面，对于这么轻的机器来说，它非常强大。
Four gigabytes of RAM with an ultra-fast processor.
四GB内存，配备超快处理器。
The most advanced video and sound cards on the market are installed with a crystal clear
安装了市场上最先进的视频和声卡，配以清晰
15 inch LCD display.
的15英寸液晶显示屏。
The X420 really stands out as a next generation laptop.
X420真正脱颖而出，是一款下一代笔记本电脑。
Compared with our previous X540 range it really is in a league of its own.
与我们之前的X540系列相比，它确实独树一帜。
Now if we go on to look at projected sales for the X420, we can see that sales revenue
现在如果我们继续看X420的预计销量，我们可以看到销售收入
for 2010 is expected to hit at least $20 million.
在2010年预计至少达到2000万美元。
Now this is really a conservative estimate.
这其实是一个保守的估计。
If our marketing campaign is successful, I'm confident that we could see a doubling of
如果我们的营销活动成功，我相信我们至少能看到这个数字
this figure at the very least.
翻倍。
Now please bear in mind that this is only for the first year of production.
现在请记住，这只是第一年的生产情况。
I'm certain that in the coming three years the X420 will actually overtake all our existing
我确信在未来三年内，X420实际上将在销售和收入方面
products both in terms of sales and revenue.
超越我们所有现有产品。
Okay now let's move on to discuss our marketing concept and look more closely at our key competitors.
好了，现在让我们继续讨论我们的营销概念，并更仔细地看看我们的主要竞争对手。
Alright we're back.
好的，我们回来了。
So we obviously heard a lot of vocab here, a lot of interesting things regarding the
所以我们显然听到了很多词汇，很多关于这台电脑的有趣内容。
computer.
Why don't we take a look at some of the words that he used on language takeaway.
我们为什么不看看他在语言学习环节中使用的一些单词呢？
Language takeaway.
语言学习环节。
So the first word that is pretty challenging is to differentiate.
第一个相当有挑战性的词是“区分”。
It's a verb.
它是一个动词。
So Mr. Ford says, ask yourself what it is that differentiates this new computer line
所以福特先生说，问问自己是什么让这个新电脑系列
with other ones.
与其他系列不同。
That's right.
没错。
So to differentiate, that means what makes it different, what is so special about it,
所以“区分”的意思是，是什么让它不同，它有什么特别之处，
right?
对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So you can ask a question like this.
所以你可以问这样一个问题。
What differentiates Apple computers from other computers?
是什么让苹果电脑与其他电脑区分开来？
That's right.
没错。
So you're asking what makes it so different.
所以你在问是什么让它如此不同。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So then he rephrases the question and he says, well in other words, what makes the X420 stand
然后他重新表述了这个问题，他说，换句话说，是什么让X420
out from all the other computers?
从所有其他电脑中脱颖而出？
All right, so this is a verbal phrase to stand out.
好的，所以这是一个动词短语“脱颖而出”。
It's very similar to the one that we just mentioned to differentiate.
它和我们刚才提到的“区分”非常相似。
This means what makes this computer special?
这意味着是什么让这台电脑特别？
Why is it unique?
为什么它独一无二？
That's right.
没错。
So we're basically saying, why is this one more noticeable than the rest?
所以我们基本上是在说，为什么这一个比其他的更引人注目？
That's to stand out.
这就是“脱颖而出”。
So maybe if everyone in the office is wearing white t-shirts today, but somebody comes in
所以如果今天办公室里每个人都穿着白色T恤，但有个人进来
wearing a red t-shirt, that person is going to stand out.
穿着红色T恤，那个人就会很突出。
Actually, Marco, I think today that's you.
实际上，Marco，我觉得今天那个人就是你。
You're wearing a red t-shirt today, so you stand out.
你今天穿了一件红色T恤，所以你很突出。
Okay.
好的。
So now as he continued to talk about the computer, he used this prefix before an adjective.
所以当他继续谈论电脑时，他在形容词前用了一个前缀。
That was very interesting.
这非常有趣。
He said, this computer is ultra light.
他说，这台电脑是超轻的。
And then he said it's ultra thin as well.
然后他还说它也是超薄的。
And that it has an ultra fast processor.
而且它有一个超快的处理器。
Okay.
好的。
So ultra light, ultra fast, ultra thin.
所以超轻、超快、超薄。
This is a way of saying very, very.
这是一种表示“非常非常”的方式。
That's right.
没错。
So that's what he's saying.
所以这就是他说的意思。
He's saying it's very light, it's very thin.
他说它非常轻，非常薄。
So that's pretty much the structure.
所以这基本上就是结构。
You can add ultra before an adjective to emphasize that it's very something.
你可以在形容词前加上“超”来强调它非常怎么样。
That's right.
没错。
So when I think of cool actors, I think of James Dean.
所以当我想到酷演员时，我会想到詹姆斯·迪恩。
He was ultra cool.
他超级酷。
Ultra cool.
超级酷。
Very cool.
非常酷。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So you can do it with pretty much all adjectives, but you can't really exaggerate and use it
所以你可以用几乎所有形容词这样做，但你不能真的夸张并一直用
all the time.
它。
Well, the key is to remember this is an exaggeration.
嗯，关键是要记住这是一种夸张。
So yeah, you don't want to use it all the time.
所以是的，你不想一直用它。
But if you want to make sure you say that something is, if you want to emphasize that
但如果你想确保你说某件事是，如果你想强调
something is special or that it's very, very something, you use the word ultra.
某件事很特别或非常非常怎么样，你就用“ultra”这个词。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
As you continue to talk about the characteristics of the laptop computer, he made reference
当你继续谈论笔记本电脑的特性时，他提到了
to the LCD display, the screen of the computer.
LCD显示屏，也就是电脑的屏幕。
And he said that it's a crystal clear 15 inch LCD display.
他说这是一个晶莹剔透的15英寸LCD显示屏。
What does he mean by crystal clear?
他说的“晶莹剔透”是什么意思？
Well, crystal is a very special kind of glass, right?
嗯，水晶是一种非常特殊的玻璃，对吧？
And so it's expensive.
所以它很贵。
It's what some people have as their special glassware, you know, wine glasses and drinking
有些人把它当作特殊的玻璃器皿，你知道，酒杯和饮用
glasses.
杯。
And so crystal is very special because it's so clear to see through.
水晶非常特别，因为它非常透明，可以看透。
So transparent.
所以是透明的。
It's transparent.
它是透明的。
Light goes through it.
光线能穿过它。
You can see everything.
你能看到一切。
And so to say something is crystal clear is to say that it's very, very clear.
所以说某物“晶莹剔透”就是说它非常非常清晰。
It's extremely clear.
它极其清晰。
It's as clear as crystal.
它像水晶一样清晰。
Okay.
好的。
So basically the screen of this computer, you can see very, very well everything that's
所以基本上这台电脑的屏幕，你能非常非常清楚地看到
on the screen, everything that's happening.
屏幕上的一切，所有发生的事情。
All the colors, all of the words.
所有的颜色，所有的文字。
Okay.
好的。
And then moving away from the characteristics of the computer, he talked about projected
然后从电脑的特性转到，他谈到了预计
sales and he expected $20 million.
销售额，他预期是2000万美元。
But he said that that is a very conservative estimate.
但他说这是一个非常保守的估计。
Okay.
好的。
So an estimate is like a guess.
所以估计就像是一个猜测。
It's how much we think we will earn in a year or how much we think will happen.
这是我们预计一年能赚多少或我们认为会发生多少。
But in this case, a conservative estimate means that it's a low estimate.
但在这个例子中，保守的估计意味着这是一个低的估计。
You know, we might make $20 million next year.
你知道，我们明年可能赚2000万美元。
That's conservative.
那是保守的。
Another estimate is we will make $40 million.
另一个估计是我们会赚4000万美元。
So that's not conservative.
所以那就不保守了。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So as you said, an estimate is we are more or less guessing how much it would be.
所以就像你说的，估计是我们或多或少猜测会是多少。
So what would be the opposite of a conservative estimate?
那么保守估计的反义词是什么？
You could say a generous estimate.
你可以说慷慨的估计。
That means you're giving a lot.
那意味着你给得很多。
Okay.
好的。
So a generous estimate is our revenues will be at around $60 million next year.
所以慷慨的估计是我们的收入明年大约在6000万美元左右。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So I think we've taken in a lot.
所以我想我们吸收了很多。
Why don't we take a break?
我们休息一下怎么样？
Let's listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
让我们再听一遍对话，然后我们会回来做流利度练习。
Now a key question you might ask yourself is what differentiates the new X420 line with
现在你可能问自己的一个关键问题是，新的X420系列与
our previous models?
我们之前的型号有什么不同？
And also, of course, with some of our competitors.
当然，还有与我们的一些竞争对手相比。
In other words, what makes the X420 stand out from all the others?
换句话说，是什么让X420从所有其他产品中脱颖而出？
This is a key question and it's something I'd like to explore in a little depth.
这是一个关键问题，也是我想深入探讨的事情。
Firstly, the X420 has a range of USPs that really make it a cut above the rest.
首先，X420有一系列独特的卖点，使它真正比其他的高出一筹。
The first thing to mention is that the X420 is the first in a new generation of ultra-light
首先要提到的是，X420是新一代超轻
laptop computers.
笔记本电脑中的第一款。
It is only two pounds, which compares very favorably with all our key competitors.
它只有两磅重，这比我们所有主要竞争对手都更有优势。
In terms of computer performance, for such a light machine, it's very powerful.
就电脑性能而言，对于这么轻的机器来说，它非常强大。
Four gigabytes of RAM with an ultra-fast processor.
四GB内存，配有一个超快处理器。
The most advanced video and sound cards on the market are installed with a crystal clear
市场上最先进的视频和声卡已安装，配有一个晶莹剔透的
15-inch LCD display.
15英寸LCD显示屏。
The X420 really stands out as a next generation laptop.
X420真正作为下一代笔记本电脑脱颖而出。
Compared with our previous X540 range, it really is in a league of its own.
与我们之前的X540系列相比，它确实自成一格。
Now if we go on to look at projected sales for the X420, we can see that sales revenue
现在如果我们继续看X420的预计销售额，我们可以看到2010年的销售收入
for 2010 is expected to hit at least $20 million.
预计至少达到2000万美元。
Now this is really a conservative estimate.
这其实是一个保守的估计。
If our marketing campaign is successful, I'm confident that we could see a doubling of
如果我们的营销活动成功，我有信心我们至少能看到这个数字
this figure at the very least.
翻倍。
Now please bear in mind that this is only for the first year of production.
现在请记住，这只是生产的第一年。
I'm certain that in the coming three years, the X420 will actually overtake all our existing
我确信在未来三年内，X420 实际上会超越我们现有的所有
products, both in terms of sales and revenue.
产品，无论是在销售额还是收入方面。
Okay, now let's move on to discuss our marketing concept and look more closely at our key competitors.
好的，现在我们继续讨论我们的营销理念，并更仔细地看看我们的主要竞争对手。
Alright we're back with Fluency Builder.
好了，我们回到流利度训练环节。
Let's take a look at some key phrases now.
现在让我们来看一些关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Alright, so our first phrase is a very important phrase when you're trying to differentiate
好的，我们的第一个短语在你要区分
different products or things.
不同产品或事物时非常重要。
We say, this is really a cut above the rest.
我们说，这真是出类拔萃。
Okay, so if something is a cut above the rest, it means that it's in a different category
好的，所以如果某物出类拔萃，意味着它属于一个不同的类别，
from everyone else.
与其他东西不同。
It's a lot better.
它好得多。
It is a lot better.
So you can say that we saw many, many applicants who wanted to come for a job at our company,
所以你可以说，我们看到了很多很多想申请我们公司工作的应聘者，
but John, he was a cut above the rest.
但约翰，他出类拔萃。
He was much better than all of the other candidates.
他比其他所有候选人都优秀得多。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So a cut above the rest.
所以是出类拔萃。
Now when we talked about this computer, he also made reference saying that it's in a
现在当我们谈论这台电脑时，他还提到说它
league of its own.
独树一帜。
The computer is so powerful, it's so new, it's so fantastic that it's in a league of
这台电脑如此强大、如此新颖、如此出色，以至于它
its own.
独树一帜。
Okay, so a league is like a category in this case.
好的，所以在这里“league”就像是一个类别。
We have good computers and we have great computers, but this computer is so good.
我们有好的电脑和优秀的电脑，但这台电脑太好了。
It's in an entirely new category.
它属于一个全新的类别。
It's awesome.
它太棒了。
It's amazing.
它令人惊叹。
It's mind blowing.
它令人震撼。
So we often say this with new things.
所以我们经常用这个来形容新事物。
This is great, but nothing before it can compare.
这很棒，但之前的东西都无法与之相比。
They're just not as good.
它们就是没那么好。
So it's in a league of its own.
所以它独树一帜。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So you can make reference to products or also people, right?
所以你可以用它来形容产品或人，对吧？
A person can be in a league of his own.
一个人可以独树一帜。
That's right.
没错。
So you know, there are a lot of good singers in the world, but this singer, he is in a
所以你知道，世界上有很多好歌手，但这位歌手，
league of his own.
他独树一帜。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And to finish off Fluency Builder, towards the end of his dialogue, he said, to please
为了结束流利度训练，在他的对话结尾，他说，
bear in mind that this is only the first year of production.
请记住这只是第一年的生产。
Okay, so we're talking about making these products.
好的，所以我们是在讨论制造这些产品。
You know, there's going to take time to make money and Mr. Ford would like us to bear
你知道，赚钱需要时间，福特先生希望我们
something in mind, to bear in mind this fact.
记住某件事，记住这个事实。
So to bear something in mind means to remember or to consider.
所以“记住某件事”意思是记住或考虑。
Okay, so he's asking us to please consider that it's only the first year of production,
好的，所以他要求我们请考虑这只是第一年的生产，
so we can't really expect too much.
所以我们不能期望太高。
That's right.
没错。
So I could talk about a number of different things.
所以我可以谈论很多不同的事情。
I could say, you know, Marco, here's my report.
我可以说，你知道，马可，这是我的报告。
Please look over it.
请过目。
Please bear in mind, this is only a first draft.
请记住，这只是初稿。
Okay, so I will make some edits, I will make some changes.
好的，所以我会做一些编辑，做一些修改。
It's not perfect and I know that.
它不完美，我知道。
So please bear this in mind.
所以请记住这一点。
Okay, so you're kind of warning me, you're kind of letting me know to consider the fact
好的，所以你是在提醒我，你是在让我考虑
that it's not the final report and there might be some mistakes.
这不是最终报告，可能有一些错误。
Exactly.
正是。
So to bear in mind that saying this is kind of like a warning that things are not perfect
所以“记住”这个说法有点像警告，事情还不完美，
yet but, you know, I still want your opinion.
但你知道，我仍然想要你的意见。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
那我们再听一遍对话，一会儿回来。
Now a key question you might ask yourself is what differentiates the new X420 line with
现在你可能问自己的一个关键问题是，新的X420系列与
our previous models and also of course with some of our competitors.
我们之前的型号以及当然一些竞争对手有什么不同。
In other words, what makes the X420 stand out from all the others?
换句话说，是什么让X420从所有其他产品中脱颖而出？
This is a key question and it's something I'd like to explore in a little depth.
这是一个关键问题，也是我想深入探讨的事情。
Firstly, the X420 has a range of USPs that really make it a cut above the rest.
首先，X420有一系列独特的卖点，使它真正出类拔萃。
The first thing to mention is that the X420 is the first in a new generation of ultra-light
首先要提到的是，X420是新一代超轻
laptop computers.
笔记本电脑中的第一款。
It is only 2 pounds which compares very favorably with all our key competitors.
它只有2磅重，这与我们所有主要竞争对手相比非常有利。
In terms of computer performance, for such a light machine, it's very powerful.
在电脑性能方面，对于这么轻的机器来说，它非常强大。
4 gigabytes of RAM with an ultra-fast processor, the most advanced video and sound cards on
4GB内存，超快处理器，市场上最先进的视频和声卡
the market are installed with a crystal clear 15-inch LCD display.
都安装有清晰15英寸液晶显示屏。
The X420 really stands out as a next generation laptop.
X420真正作为下一代笔记本电脑脱颖而出。
Compared with our previous X540 range, it really is in a league of its own.
与我们之前的X540系列相比，它真是独树一帜。
Now if we go on to look at projected sales for the X420, we can see that sales revenue
现在如果我们继续看X420的预计销量，我们可以看到2010年的销售收入
for 2010 is expected to hit at least $20 million.
预计至少达到2000万美元。
Now this is really a conservative estimate.
这其实是一个保守的估计。
If our marketing campaign is successful, I'm confident that we could see a doubling of
如果我们的营销活动成功，我相信我们至少能看到
this figure at the very least.
这个数字翻倍。
Now please bear in mind that this is only for the first year of production.
请注意，这只是第一年生产的情况。
I'm certain that in the coming 3 years, the X420 will actually overtake all our existing
我确信在未来三年内，X420 实际上会超越我们现有的所有
products, both in terms of sales and revenue.
产品，无论是在销售还是收入方面。
Ok, now let's move on to discuss our marketing concept and look more closely at our key competitors.
好的，现在我们继续讨论营销概念，并更仔细地看看我们的主要竞争对手。
We're back.
我们回来了。
Now you've probably saw this acronym in the very first part of the dialogue when he said
你可能在对话的第一部分就看到了这个缩写，当时他说
that the X420 has a range of USPs that really make it a cut above the rest.
X420 有一系列独特卖点，让它真正脱颖而出。
Alright, so this is a very special acronym for the business world and it stands for U
好的，这是商业世界中一个非常特别的缩写，它代表 U
– Unique, S – Selling, and P – Point.
– 独特，S – 销售，P – 点。
Unique Selling Point.
独特卖点。
That's right.
没错。
So as the name says, a unique selling point are characteristics that are unique to the
顾名思义，独特卖点是指该机器独有的特性，
machine that allow it to be more competitive and to persuade people to buy it or to sell
使其更具竞争力，并说服人们购买它或推销
itself.
它自己。
So the new iPhone has a very interesting unique selling point.
所以新款 iPhone 有一个非常有趣的独特卖点。
It has two cameras, one on the front and one on the back.
它有两个摄像头，一个在前面，一个在后面。
So that really differentiates it from other phones on the market.
这确实让它与市场上的其他手机区别开来。
That's right.
没错。
So that is what a USP is or a unique selling point.
这就是 USP 或独特卖点的含义。
As we said, it's an acronym in the business world, but next time that you find the opportunity
正如我们所说，这是商业世界中的一个缩写，但下次你有机会
to use it, I'm sure it's going to sound amazing.
使用它时，我相信它会听起来很棒。
Yes, very professional.
是的，非常专业。
USP, Unique Selling Point.
USP，独特卖点。
Alright so that's all the time we have.
好的，我们时间到了。
Be sure to check out the next part of our series next week and of course if you have
请务必在下周查看我们系列的下一部分，当然，如果你有
any questions or comments, you're always welcome at EnglishPod.com.
任何问题或评论，随时欢迎访问 EnglishPod.com。
We will see you there.
我们会在那里见。
Bye guys.
再见，各位。
Enjoy your day.
祝你们愉快。